

Abdul Wahab

Full Stack Developer

Done Masters in Web Engineering and Bachelors in Software Engineering, Learning day by day new technologies. Finding a career path in Software Development. *Innovative and deadline-driven web developer with 3+ years of experience designing and developing websites and software from initial concept to final, polished deliverable.*

≥ abwahab1995@gmail.com

Traubestraße 17, Dresden, Germany

in linkedin.com/in/abdul-wahab

015734931451

abproxer.github.io/profile/

S ab_proxer@outlook.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer twentyZen GmbH

01/2021 - Present

Dresden, Germany

Tasks

- React, Javascript
- RESTful APIs using NodeRed
- PHP
- Data Warehousing

Tools: VS Code, WinSCP, NodeRed, Confluence, Jira, MS-SQL, PowerBI

Work Student

inovisio communications GmbH 🗷

05/2020 - 08/2020 Chemnitz, Germany

Tasks

- web application Testing (Selenium)
- Javascript
- PHP (Laminas Framework)
- mysql

Tools: VS Code, Selenium, mysql, Conflunce, wiki docs

IT Internee

Parker Hannifin Manufacturing Germany GmbH ♂

10/2019 - 04/2020

Chemnitz, Germany

Tasks

- power BI Reporting Server and power BI Desktop,
- C# and VBA for creating Macros
- Microsoft SQL, SSIS

Tools: VS Code, Xampp, Filezilla, PowerBI, MS Report Builder, SSIS, MySQL

EDUCATION

Masters in Web Engineering

Technische Universität Chemnitz

11/2017 - 08/2020 Chemnitz, Germany

Courses

Software enginnering
 Web Development

Bachelors in SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

National University of Modern Languages 🗷

Courses

06/2012 - 09/2016

 Database Management Systems Software Engineering Practice

Islamabad, Pakistan

TECHNICAL SKILLS



PROJECTS

MeetMe React Application

 Web based web portal in react to post new meetups and and add the posted meetups in the favorites.

Data Scraping for Restaurants Website

 Project to create a website where all scraped and cleaned data show through REST API in the fornend.

Visualization and Warehousing of Scientific Research

- Master Thesis

ACHIEVEMENTS

Head of IT skills in University

Served as a Head of IT skills in University society of Engineers.

Third position in Open House 2016

Third position in Open House 2016 held in National University of Modern Languages

LANGUAGES

English Germa

Professional Working Proficiency Elementary Proficiency

Urdu

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

INTERESTS

Computer Gaming IT News Cricket GYM

Communication Travelling